Matthew 16
You are the Christ, the Son of the living God.
And Jesus answered him,
Blessed are you, Simon Barjona,
for flesh and blood has not revealed this to you,
but my Father who is in heaven.
And I tell you, you are Peter,
and on this rock I will build my church,
and the gates of hell shall not prevail against it.
I will give you the keys of the kingdom of heaven,
and whatever you bind on earth shall be bound in heaven.
And whatever you loose on earth shall be loosed in heaven.
Then he strictly charged the disciples to tell no one
that he was the Christ.
From that time Jesus began to show his disciples
that he must go to Jerusalem and suffer many things
from the elders and chief priests and scribes
and be killed and on the third day be raised.
And Peter took him aside and began to rebuke him,
saying,
Far be it from you, Lord.
This shall never happen to you.
But he turned and said to Peter,
Get behind me, Satan.
You are a hindrance to me,
for you are not setting your mind on the things of God,
but on the things of man.
Then Jesus told his disciples,
If anyone would come after me,
let him deny himself and take up his cross and follow me.
For whoever would save his life,
will lose it.
But whoever loses his life for my sake will find it.
For what will it profit a man
if he gains the whole world and forfeits his soul?
Or what shall a man give in return for his soul?
For the Son of Man is going to come with his angels
in the glory of his Father,
and then he will repay each person according to what he has done.
Truly I say to you,
there are some standing here
who will not taste death
until they see the Son of Man coming in his kingdom.